

Sakari Cajanus scajanus@gmail.com sakaricajanus.com +358503083440

In January 2017, I left Finland to do something else for a while.

I worked on Cat Ba in Vietnam as a guide for climbing and kayaking, and then traveled and climbed in Middle East and South East Asia.

Now, I feel it is time to work with data again.

## Sakari Cajanus

### Data Scientist - Curriculum Vitae

**About Me** I have a degree in Biomedical Engineering from Aalto University, where I studied modelling biological networks and computational genomics. Since then, I have used the knowledge in the field of marine industry. I have worked in research, and as an analyst, product manager and software developer.

## **Experience**

February 2017 – August 2017, *Adventure Guide*, Asia Outdoors February 2014 – January 2017, *Several positions*, Eniram Ltd. Product manager:

- Product management of Models and Data Processing teams
- Product owner of statistical models and data processing software
- Worked with other product managers and CTO to satisfy customer needs, prioritize development tasks and deliver on time

#### Software developer:

- Developed software for data analysis in Python and Matlab
- Moved software to production, planned roadmaps
- Developed minimum viable product for delivering push notifications to a mobile app.

#### Analyst:

- Delivered reports to customers on time and with accuracy
- Tracked, diagnosed and fixed data quality issues
- Focus on fuel savings and system usage, including comparisons between vessels

# June 2013 – November 2013, *Master's Thesis Worker*, Polar Electro Oy

Studied the data and the extent to which it is used in the company. Identified opportunities where data could be used to improve customer experience and marketing.

May 2011 – Dec 2012, *Research Assistant at BECS*, Aalto University Used point pattern and spatial models for human communication and nerve fiber data. Used both MATLAB and R for statistical analysis.

### **Education**

2015, Aalto University

Master of Science (Tech.) in Bioinformation Technology

2012, Aalto University

Bachelor of Science (Tech.) in Bioinformation Technology

## **Software Development Skills**

#### **Programming**

- Python
- Matlab
- $\circ$  R

- o C & C++
- SQL
- Java



Sakari Cajanus scajanus@gmail.com sakaricajanus.com +358503083440

In January 2017, I left Finland to do something else for a while.

I worked on Cat Ba in Vietnam as a guide for climbing and kayaking, and then traveled and climbed in Middle East and South East Asia.

Now, I feel it is time to work with data again.

## **Positions of Trust**

2016, Vice Chairman, Contractura climbing club2016, Member of Delegation, Medical student association2011, Member of the Board, Inkubio ry., student association

## Language skills

#### **Fluent**

Finnish (mother tongue), English as work language for 7 years Conver-

#### sational

German – can follow most conversations, speak basic German

Swedish – the same, but worse